(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963) 11x01 The Time Warrior (Part 1)
《神秘博士》老版第十一季第一集 《时间勇士》 (第一部分)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
基于opensubtitles.org 英文字幕翻译
This sheep has been dead a year.
Are they trying to poison me?
这头羊都死了一年了吧。他们这是打算毒死我吗？
It is salted.
这是腌制过的
Salted? It stinks!
腌过的? 太臭了
Wine! Must I perish of thirst? Bring me wine!
酒！必须得让我渴死吗？拿酒来！
'Tis the dregs of the barrel, Captain.
'Tis the last there is.
这是桶底的残余, 头儿。这是最后的一点儿
(GROWLING)
Sour wine! Stinking meat!
酒是酸的, 肉是臭的！
Sour wine! Is this how I'm served?
酸酒！我就只能得到这样服侍吗？
Our supplies are low, Captain.
It's some time since we went aforaging.
我们的供应不足, 头儿。我们四处搜罗已经有一段时间了
Meanwhile our fine neighbours feast their bellies
full on fresh meat
为什么我们的邻居这个时候肚子里装满了鲜肉
and swill down flagons of fine wine.
杯子里晃荡着美酒？
Well, Sir Edward's storehouses and cellars are well-stocked.
是啊, Edward 爵士的仓库和酒窖储备都很充足
Then perhaps we should relieve him
of some of his abundance, eh, my friend?
那或许我们应该帮他减轻一点负担啊, 对不, 我的朋友？
He's a good neighbour. He'll not miss a little of his plenty.
他是一个好邻居啊。他那么多东西, 丢掉一点点他也不会在意的
Look!
看！
(WHIRRING)
Stars are falling!
星星都掉下来了！
I see only one star.
我只看到一颗星
It has fallen in the forest!
它掉到森林里面去了！
Come on, get up. Get up! Get up!
快来, 起来, 起来！起来！
It is an omen.
这是个征兆
- An evil sign! - It is mine.
- 这是个邪恶的符号！  - 它是我的
Irongron's star. I will have it!
是我 Irongron 的星星。我要拿到它！
- Hurry. Fetch the horses.
- Hurry? Hurry where?
- 快点, 牵马过来  - 快点？快点去哪儿？
To find the star before some knave robs me of it.
It landed close by.
去找星星, 免得一会儿被些混混给抢走了。它落在附近了
But the forest is still in darkness.
Who knows what demons may set upon us?
但森林还黑着呢, 谁知道会不会有恶魔在等着我们？
Why, you chicken-hearted knaves, every man of you!
啥？你们这些鼠胆, 你们所有人都是！
It's but an hour till dawn! Let's wait till then.
还有不到一小时就天亮了！ 我们等一会儿吧
To wait and see what faces us. We'll follow you then, Captain.
等一等再看那里有什么, 那时候我们会跟你去的, 头儿
Let all be made ready. I ride at dawn. - Alone if need be.
把一切都准备好, 天一亮我就要 —— 没人我就自己去
We're with you, Captain.
我们会跟着你的, 头儿
Then bring me some wine.
那再给我来点酒
We'll drink a toast to Irongron's star.
我们为 Irongron 的星星喝一杯
A star. A fallen star.
星星, 一颗坠落的星星
Careful, Captain, looks like the devil's work to me.
小心点, 头儿, 看起来像是魔鬼的杰作
A warrior? A warrior from the stars!
Have you come to challenge me?
一位勇士？从星星上来的勇士！你是来向我挑战的吗？
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
Flee for your life, Captain!
逃命要紧啊, 头儿！
- What creature is this?
- 'Tis a devil from hell.
- 这是什么怪物？   - 这是地狱来的魔鬼
Peace.
冷静
Fear not. I shall not harm you.
不用害怕, 我不会伤害你的
It speaks. Who are you? Where do you come from?
它会说话。你是谁？你从哪里来的？
I am a Sontaran officer.
我是一个桑塔军官
My name is Linx.
我的名字是 Linx
I say he's a Saracen. I have heard tales of his Eastern magic.
我觉得他是个撒拉逊人, 我听说过他那些东方魔法的传说
By virtue of my authority as an officer of the Army Space Corps,
凭着陆军太空军团军官的权威
I hereby claim this planet, its moons and satellites
我在此宣布这个星球, 以及它的月亮和卫星
for the greater glory of the Sontaran Empire.
都属于伟大光荣的桑塔帝国
Help you? Why should I help you, star warrior?
帮你？为什么我要帮你, 星星勇士？
Why should I not kill you and take your ship
and its treasure for myself?
为什么我不杀了你, 抢走你的船和船里的宝贝呢？
LINX: The ship is in need of repair.
这艘船需要维修
Even if it were not, you would destroy
yourself should you tamper with it.
即使它不需要维修, 你去动它的话你同样会完蛋
Then why should I not just slay you for sport?
那要不然我就只宰掉你, 寻个开心？
Can you overcome all of us with your magic?
你能搞定我们所有人吗 — 用你的“魔法”？
LINX: You are a soldier, are you not? A warrior?
你是一个战士, 对不？一个勇士？
I took this castle by force of arms.
我凭着武力夺下了这座城堡
Those that were here before me, I slew.
之前这里的人, 都被我赶回去了
All the countryside around here pays my tribute.
周边的村子都要给我上贡
Yet no doubt you have enemies?
那你肯定有敌人吧？
Other warriors who envy your good fortune?
有一些勇士会嫉妒于你的好运？
Aye, but they cannot harm me.
是有, 不过他们伤害不了我
The king has levied tribute.
All their troops are at the wars.
国王四处征收, 他们的人也在四处忙着打仗
And when they return?
那他们回来之后呢？
Then we shall fight.
那我们就会战斗
I can give you weapons,
我可以给你武器
weapons that can make you masters,
so that none dare stand against you.
这些武器可以让你成为主人, 没人再敢站出来反对你
You shall take what castles you will.
你想要哪座城堡都没问题了
Magic weapons? Like that, that smote the sword from my hand?
魔法武器吗？ 就像那种...无形中击飞我的剑的那种？
Other weapons fitter for your purpose.
还有其它符合你需要的武器
Weapons that can strike a man dead from far away.
于远处夺人性命那种武器
- You can be supreme warrior.
- I can be king.
- 你就可以成为超级勇士了 - 我还可以成国王哩
But what do you ask in return, apart from your life?
但你需要什么作为回报呢, 除了饶你不死之外？
Shelter.
庇护
A place to conceal my ship and help with its repair.
需要一个地方把我的飞船藏起来, 还需要有人帮忙进行维修
- You have men that can work in metal?
- An armourer to sharpen weapons,
- 你有人会锻造金属不？ - 有个会打造武器的
a smith with a forge if these will serve your need.
有铁匠和熔炉, 应该能满足你的需要了
I need more, much more.
我需要很多, 非常多
There is damage to the drive mechanism of my ship.
我的飞船的驱动系统受损了
I need alloy, skilled technicians, complex circuitry.
我需要合金, 需要技工, 还有人对付复杂的电路
Oh, we have none of these things of which you speak.
哦, 你说的这些我们一样也没有
Then I must take them from those who have.
那我只能自己找了
In here, Brigadier?
是这里吗, 准将？
Yes, I'm afraid so, Doctor. Not exactly the Ritz, I know,
是的, 恐怕是这样, 博士。不是值得炫耀的地方, 我知道
but it's no joke providing emergency accommodation
for all these scientists.
但要给这么多科学家提供紧急住所, 也不是容易的事情
All right, Brigadier,
you've had your little bit of mystification.
好吧, 准将, 你已经完成了你的小奇迹
Now I know where I'm supposed to stay,
perhaps you wouldn't mind telling me why?
现在我知道我应该呆在哪里了。但或许你能告诉我这都是为什么？
This place is one of the most top secret
security establishments in the whole country.
这个地方是全国最绝密的安全机构之一
Most of their work is so secret,
这里的人所做的事情是如此机密
they don't know what they're doing themselves.
他们自己都不知道自己在做些什么
And?
怎么？
It's also one of the best-guarded places in the country.
这里也是全国安保措施最好的地方之一
Security details, alarm systems...
安全检查, 告警系统...
I rather gathered that when we arrived.
我们到这里的时候我都注意到了
For a moment I thought they weren't going to let you in.
有那么一会儿我以为他们连你都不允许进来了
Yes, exactly. The place is almost too security conscious.
是的, 的确如此, 这个地方似乎在安全上有点过于过分了
That's what makes it all the more puzzling.
但这就使得问题更加令人困惑了
Makes what all the more puzzling?
使得什么问题更令人困惑？
Come on, Brigadier, you can tell me.
好啦, 准将, 你可以跟我说的
- People vanishing.
- People?
- 有人消失  - 有人？
Well, they've lost. Half a dozen leading scientists
是的, 他们不见了。半打顶尖科学家
and several million pounds' worth of ultra-secret equipment.
还有几百万英镑的超级机密设备
What are they working on here anyway?
他们到底在这里是研究什么的？
Space hardware. New alloys, guidance systems,
methods of propulsion.
太空材料、新型合金、导航系统、太空推进器等
- And what action have you taken so far?
- Well, I had rather a bright idea.
- 目前位置你都采取了什么措施没有？  - 哦, 我有一个不错的想法
It's pretty hard to keep an eye
on all these scientist chaps at home,
如果让这些科学家呆在家里, 我们很难全部盯住他们
so I had these cubicles put up on several floors.
所以我让人在这几层搭了这些小格间
Confined the whole lot to barracks,
all my eggs in one basket so to speak.
把这些人都圈到这里, 简单地说, 所有的鸡蛋都到一个篮子了
That's fine, so long as no one steals the basket.
这不错啊——如果没人能偷走这个篮子的话
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Linx! My Lord Linx!
Linx！Linx 大人!
Will you open the door?
你能打开门吗？
LINX: None may enter here.
Such was my agreement with your captain.
没人可以进来。这是我跟你们头领达成的协议
Yay, it is my captain who sent me.
知道, 但正是我们头儿派我来的
He would have words with you, Lord Linx.
他想跟你谈谈, Linx 大人
Then tell him I'm occupied. Now leave me to my work.
那告诉他我没空, 别打扰我工作
(BANGS ON DOOR)
Insolent primitives. Did I not need their aid...
无礼的原始人。我干脆不要他们帮忙算了...
Where is the star warrior?
星星勇士在哪儿？
He would not come. He says he's occupied.
他不肯来, 他说他正忙
Oh, the insolent barbarian.
Did I not need his help, I'd...
噢, 无礼的野蛮人。我不要他的帮助, 我要...
See, Bloodaxe. The first of the new weapons.
你看, Bloodaxe, 第一批新武器
Watch!
看着！
Oh! Claps the ears!
噢, 捂住耳朵！
I'll soon master the aim.
我很快就能瞄得准了
Rubeish.
- I beg your pardon?
- Joseph Rubeish.
- 对不起没听清 - 我叫Joseph Rubeish
Oh, I see. I'm so sorry. Hello. How do you do?
哦, 明白了, 对不起。嗨, 你好
It's disgraceful, of course. Utterly disgraceful.
这太不恰当了, 的确, 非常不恰当
Oh? What is?
噢？什么？
Well, shutting us up. Like a lot of kids kept in after school.
不让我们说话, 就好像我们放学后被留住的小孩子似的
And that brigadier chap, military idiot.
就那个准将, 没脑子的军人
Yes, I know how you feel. Still, he means well, you know.
是的, 我知道你的感受。不过, 他本意是好的, 你也知道
Haven't seen my wife and family for three days.
我都三天没见过我的老婆和家人了
I'm sorry to hear that.
很抱歉听到这个
Ah, well, just shows there's always a silver lining.
啊, 好吧, 还算是有一线希望
- And your name?
- Uh, Smith, Dr John Smith.
- 你的名字是？ - 噢, 史密斯, 约翰-史密斯博士
- Seems to be a lot of them about today.
- I'm sorry?
- 今天这里好像有好多史密斯  - 什么？
I was talking to a young woman just now, also Smith.
我刚才还跟一个年轻女人说话, 也叫史密斯
- Well, there she is. Miss Smith?
- Yes, Professor?
- 喏, 她来了。史密斯小姐？  - 什么事, 教授？
Come and meet your namesake.
过来见见你的本家
- Miss Lavinia Smith, Doctor, uh...
- Dr John Smith.
- 我是 Lavinia Smith, 你是。。  - 约翰-史密斯博士
- How do you do, Miss Smith?
- Hello.
- 你好, 史密斯小姐  - 你好
Doctor, I'm intrigued. What's that for?
博士, 我很好奇, 那是做什么用的？
That? Oh, that, that contains my equipment, Professor.
那个, 哦, 那个是用来装我的设备的, 教授
That's original.
这倒没见过
- You're the virologist, Miss Smith?
- Yes.
- 你是个病毒学家, 史密斯小姐？ - 是的
Who told you?
谁告诉你的？
I read your paper on the teleological response of the virus,
我读过你那篇关于病毒的远程响应(??)方面的论文
- a most impressive piece of work.
- Thank you.
- 令人非常印象深刻 - 谢谢你
Particularly when I realised,
you must have written it when you were five years old.
尤其是我意识到, 你写那篇论文的时候应该才五岁
Ah, uh... Yes, that is rather difficult to explain, isn't it?
啊, 喔...是的, 这的确很难解释, 是吧
You're going to try, aren't you?
你不尝试解释一下吗？
Well, um... My Aunt Lavinia is in America
on a lecture tour, you see.
是这样, 唔...我的姨妈 Lavinia 因为要搞一个讲座去美国了, 明白吗
- Mmm-hmm.
- She had an invitation to visit here.
- 嗯哼  - 她有这里的邀请函
- I took her place.
- Why?
- 于是我就来了  - 为什么？
I thought all this might give me a good story.
我觉得这些会让我得到一个好故事
I'm a journalist. Sarah Jane Smith.
我是个新闻记者, 莎拉-简-史密斯
You realise this is a very dangerous place to be in?
你应该知道你呆的这个地方是非常危险的吧？
Well, I can't help that. I'm stuck here now.
只是, 我忍不住。不过现在被困住了
Anyway, we've got all these soldiers looking after us.
不管怎样, 我们还有这么些士兵保护着我们呢
Are you going to give me away, Doctor?
你会告发我吗, 博士？
- I don't think so.
- Why not?
- 我没这么想   - 为什么呢？
Well, you can make yourself useful.
嗯, 也许你能派上点用场
We need somebody around here to make the coffee.
我们这里需要有人泡个咖啡什么的
If you think I'm going to spend my time
making cups of coffee for you...
如果你觉得我会浪费我的时间来给你们泡咖啡的话...
Professor!
教授！
Would you kindly desist? This is not a blackboard, you know.
你能否好心放过它, 它并不是一块黑板, 你知道吧
Oh, I do beg your pardon, Doctor. I was just trying to prove...
哦, 请你原谅, 博士, 我只是想证明...
What are you going to do in there?
你打算在那里面做什么呢？
Make myself a cup of coffee. Good day to you.
给我自己泡一杯咖啡。祝你今天过得愉快
But for how long, Edward?
但是要多久, 爱德华？
How long are we to tolerate this upstart,
this insolent usurper, as our neighbour?
我们还要忍受这种毫无教养的野蛮邻居多久？
He robs, he pillages, he murders.
He flouts your authority every day,
他每日烧杀抢掠, 他蔑视你的权威
your authority which comes from the King.
你的权力是国王授予的啊
Unfortunately, my dear, the king who gave me my authority
很不幸, 亲爱的, 授予我权力的国王
has taken away my troops to fight in his interminable wars.
已经把我的人马都带到他那无尽的战争中去了
Irongron's band is small and we still have Hal the archer,
Irgonron 的团伙很小, 而且我们还有弓箭手 Hal
and one or two men-at-arms.
和一两个能拿武器的
I've sent letters to all our neighbours.
我已经给周边的邻居都送了信了
Each, like myself, has but a mere handful of men,
他们, 跟我们一样, 都还有几个人
yet if all these handfuls be combined,
如果这些人联合起来
they might yet make a force that will crush this Irongron.
也许能够形成一股可以打垮 Irongron 的力量
If you will excuse me, my dear, I must give orders for dinner.
我先退下了, 亲爱的, 我必须得让准备晚餐了
We caught this little rabbit in the forest, sire.
我们在林子里抓到了这个小兔子, 大人
Sir Edward's squire.
爱德华爵士的小跟班
- Are you loyal to your lord, boy?
- I am.
- 你对你家大人忠诚吗, 孩子？ - 是的
We shall see.
我们来看看
He carried this. He tried to eat it when we caught him.
他带着这个。我们抓到他的时候他想吞了它
Are Sir Edward's men so ill-fed?
爱德华爵士的人都这么面黄肌瘦的吗？
Bah! I make nothing of their Norman scribbles.
啊！我认不出这些诺曼人潦草的字迹
- What's it say?
- I cannot read, Captain.
- 上面说什么  - 我不识字, 头儿
What's the message say, boy?
这信里说什么, 孩子？
So your Sir Edward is going to attack me, eh?
这么说你家爱德华爵士打算来攻打我, 是不？
Well, speak.
怎样, 说话
I know nothing.
我什么也不知道
Take him below. We'll loosen his tongue presently.
带他下去。我们很快就能撬开他的舌头
- Edward.
- What is it? Is Eric back?
- 爱德华  - 什么事, Eric 回来了吗？
- You haven't eaten all day.
- Why does he not return?
- 你一整天都没有吃东西了  - 为什么他还没有回来？
I could have ridden to my Lord
of Salisbury's castle three times over.
这时间都够跑索尔兹伯里城堡三个来回了
- It's not good for you to worry so much.
- How can I not worry?
- 你这么担忧并没有什么好处  - 我怎么才能不担忧呢？
Think that tomorrow will be brighter.
想想明天会更好
Edward, I've heard that Irongron
walks his battlements every morning.
爱德华, 我听说 Irongron 每天早上都练兵
Oh, it pleases him to be high. He's like a cockerel.
哦, 他就喜欢那样, 像个好斗的小公鸡
But does he climb so high that an arrow cannot reach him?
但他爬得太高了, 箭都射不到?
LINX: Irongron.
(IRONGRON CHUCKLING)
That strange armour you wear suits you, Linx.
你这身奇怪的盔甲倒是很适合你, Linx
- It is Sontaran space armour.
- But why must we never see your face?
- 这是桑塔人的太空服  - 不过为什么我们从来没见过你的面容？
This helmet conceals the fact
that I am not of your kind, Irongron.
这个头盔已经说明了, 我跟你们不是同一个种族, Irongron
You might not find my true appearance pleasing.
你可能会发现我的真实面貌并不会令你愉悦
(CHUCKLING) By my sword, Linx,
I'll wage you're the fairest beauty in the castle.
以我的剑作见证, Linx, 我得说你是这座城堡最漂亮的
Why did you summon me? You know my work is pressing.
你为什么叫我来？你知道我的工作很紧
I have a prisoner in the dungeon,
a surly fellow who will not speak.
我的地牢里有个囚犯, 他死活不肯开口
- And you wish him to?
- Yes.
- 那你希望他开口？  - 是的
Then give him to me. I will make him speak.
那把他交给我吧, 我会让他说话的
Tell Bloodaxe to bring up the prisoner.
告诉 Bloodaxe 把囚犯带上来
Well, Linx, you cunning old devil,
好了, Linx, 你这狡猾的老魔鬼,
what fresh tricks can you show Irongron, eh?
有什么新花招展示给 Irongron 呢？
What is the nature of the information you seek?
你想要获得哪方面的信息？
He's a messenger of those who plot a war against me.
有人正在谋划一场反对我的战争, 他就是给他们传信的
A war? That is excellent.
一场战争？那太好了
- Oh, so you like war, eh?
- Who does not?
- 噢, 看来你喜欢战争, 啊？  - 谁不喜欢呢？
My race has been at war for millennia.
我的族人已经打了近千年的仗了
There is not a galaxy in the universe
which our space fleets have not subjugated.
这个宇宙里没有一个星系, 未被我们的太空舰队征服过
But you do not understand me.
但你听不懂我在说什么
I am stranded on this primitive planet
我被困在这个原始的星球上
when I should be leading my squadron to glory.
而我原本应该带着我的小分队迈向光荣
- I am an expert at war, Irongron.
- I know.
- 我是战争方面的专家, Irongron  - 我知道
What about those weapons you promised me?
你许诺给我的武器怎么样了？
Keep your side of the bargain, I shall keep mine.
你兑现你那一方的承诺, 我也兑现我的
You shall have your weapons.
你会得到你想要的武器
(GROWLING)
We make good allies, Linx.
Each has much that the other wants.
我们的联盟很不错, Linx, 每一边都有对方想要的东西
- Miss Smith...
- No, no, I'm the Doctor.
- 史密斯小姐  - 不, 不, 我是博士
You really must keep your glasses
on the end of your nose, Professor.
你真的要把你的眼镜固定在你的鼻子上, 教授
No, no. Listen, she's not Miss Smith.
不, 不, 听着, 她不是史密斯小姐
- She isn't?
- No. Who is she?
- 她不是？ - 不是, 她是谁？
I don't think I quite understand
what you're talking about, Professor.
我觉得我没太搞明白你在说什么, 教授
Just now I was in the common room with Sir Maxwell Dingle.
刚才我跟 Maxwell Dingle 爵士在客厅
I happened to mention I was on the same landing
with Lavinia Smith, the virologist.
我无意中提起我跟病毒学家 Lavinia Smith 住在一起
- And do you know what he says?
- Yes. He said that she's in America.
- 你知道他说什么？  - 知道, 他说她现在正在美国呢
He said she's in... How could you know?
他说她现在在...你怎么知道的？
Please be careful! This is very delicate equipment.
小心一点！这是非常精巧的设备
What if she's a spy? What do we do?
如果她是一个间谍怎么办？我们该做什么？
- Shoot her?
- Ha! There's something odd about her.
- 枪杀她？ - 哈, 她是有点奇怪
She even tried to tell me you were a spy.
她还试着跟我说过, 说你是个间谍
Am I on the right floor?
我没走错楼层吧？
- Good night.
- Good night, Professor.
- 晚安  - 晚安, 教授
- What's that?
- That's my alarm clock.
- 那是什么？  - 那是我的告警钟
Oh, Doctor, kindly don't be so patronising.
Now, what is it really?
哦, 博士, 不要这么拒人千里嘛。说真的, 这是什么？
It's a rhondium sensor. It detects delta particles.
这是一个铑探测器, 它可以检测到德尔塔粒子
At a preset spectrum density of 1 5 ams,
只要浓度达到预设的15am
it oscillates this little cylinder there,
这里的小棍就会振动
which promotes a vacuum in there, which wakes me up. Clear?
从而推动这个真空管, 从而向我发出告警, 清楚了吗？
Why do you want to be woken up
when it detects delta particles?
为什么你想要它检测到德尔塔粒子就向你告警
Because I am very fond of delta particles.
因为我非常喜欢德尔塔粒子
- Why do you ask so many questions?
- Because I'm a journalist.
- 为什么你要问这么多问题  - 因为我是个新闻记者
- Are you going to sleep there?
- If you'll allow me to do so.
- 那你打算睡在那里吗？  - 如果你允许的话
Good night, Miss Smith.
晚安,史密斯小姐
Psst.
扑哧
Shouldn't we tell the Brigadier?
我们不是应该通知准将吗？
- Tell the Brigadier what?
- About her.
- 通知准将什么？  - 她的事
I think we can decide what to do about Miss Smith
我想我们能决定拿史密斯小姐怎么办
in the morning, Professor, if we're all still here.
到了明早就能决定了, 教授 —— 如果我们还在这里的话
He has a stout heart, this one, sire. He speaks not a word.
他骨头还挺硬啊, 大人。一个字也不说
Good. A fair measure for you, Linx.
好, 就看你的了, Linx
(HUMMING)
Well, come on, Linx, have at him!
嘿, 快啊, Linx, 对付他！
- Ask what you wish.
- Eh?
- 想问什么就问吧  - 嗯？
But you've done nothing.
你什么也没干啊
This is a key. I have unlocked your prisoner's mind.
这是一把钥匙, 我已经解开了这个囚徒的大脑
Question him.
问吧
How many men guard Sir Edward's castle?
爱德华爵士的城堡有多少人守卫？
There are but 10, old men for the most part.
只有不到10个人, 其中大部分还是老人
And he plans to attack me with 10 old men?
那他就打算用这10个老人来攻打我？
He sends messages to raise a force against you.
他送信让召集人马来对付你
If he succeed, then he will attack.
如果他成功了, 就会发起攻击
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
Listen to the fellow! He cannot stop babbling.
听听这个家伙！他还真是能巴巴
Stay, Linx! Have I given you leave?
别走, Linx! 我说过让你走了吗？
Each of us has work to do, Irongron. I will be back.
我们都还有事情要做, Irongron, 我得回去了
By my sword, Bloodaxe,
对我的剑发誓, Bloodaxe
I'll pickle that insolent star warrior in boiling oil one day!
某一天我要把这个无礼的星星勇士泡到滚烫的油锅里面去！
Insolent dog!
无礼的刍狗！
(SNORING)
(PULSING)
Rubeish?
- Rubeish!
- What? Who is it?
- Rubeish! - 什么事？谁啊？
Oh, it's all right. Nothing to worry about. Just checking.
哦, 没事了。没什么可担心的, 我只是检查一下
- What's happening?
- You're asking questions again.
- 怎么了？ - 你又有问题要问了
(PULSE ACCELERATING)
(CRASHING)
- Professor Rubeish?
- Rubeish!
- Rubeish 教授?  - Rubeish!
- He's gone!
- Yes.
- 他不见了 - 是的
He was here a moment ago.
一秒钟以前他还在这里呢
He can't have gone far.
他应该不会走远
He's as blind as a bat without his glasses.
不带眼镜的话, 他会跟蝙蝠一样瞎
You stay here, Miss Smith. I'm going to check the landing.
你呆在这里, 史密斯小姐。我去检查一下楼层入口
- Anybody come out of here just now?
- No.
- 刚才有谁从这里出来吗？  - 没有
(BEEPING)
(BEEPING ACCELERATING)
- What were they shooting at?
- Shadows.
- 他们在朝什么开枪呢？ - 影子
Oh, come on, Doctor, stop treating me like a child.
哦, 得了, 博士, 别当我是小孩子
I can't understand why the definition was so low.
我不明白清晰度为什么这么低
Unless he's operating with a very weak
power source at maximum range.
除非他电力不足, 同时又将功率开到了最大
- Yes, of course.
- BRIGADIER: Doctor?
- 是了, 肯定是  - 博士？
- Doctor?
- Hello!
- 博士？  - 哈喽
Look, Doctor, we've had a raid.
Is everyone present on this landing?
看, 博士, 我们刚搞了一趟搜捕。这层楼每个人都还在吗？
No. Professor Rubeish is missing.
不, Rubeish 教授不见了
Oh, my giddy aunt! The Minister will go spare.
哦, 我滴个婶婶！部长又要发飙了
Did you see anything, Doctor?
你看到什么了吗, 博士？
- Yes.
- What?
- 是的 - 什么？
Well, I thought I saw a man in armour.
哦, 我想我看到一个穿着盔甲的人
- A man in armour?
- Mmm-hmm.
- 穿盔甲的人 - 嗯哼
You mean old-fashioned armour? You mean a ghost?
你是说老式盔甲？一个鬼魂？
Oh, I very much doubt it.
哦, 对此我很怀疑
- Sorry I can't stop, Brigadier.
- Why? Where are you going?
- 抱歉我不能耽搁了, 准将  - 为什么？你要去哪儿？
Well, I've got to get on the trail while it's still warm.
我要去追踪痕迹, 趁它还没有消失
What trail? The chap's just vanished.
什么痕迹？那个家伙已经消失了
No, he hasn't. I just got a fix on him.
不, 他还没有, 我已经锁定住他了
There's something very odd indeed going on.
不过的确有一些奇怪的事情
Yes. Well, if I may say so, Doctor, that is not exactly news to me.
是啊, 让我说的话, 这对我也不是新闻了
Someone's operating a matter transmitter.
有人在使用某种物质传送器
And the really odd thing is there's a time transference, too.
真正奇怪的事情是这里还有时间的迁移
It's being worked from several centuries ago,
past and present mixed up.
是从几个世纪以前发起的, 过去与现在交织在一起了
- DOCTOR: Very interesting that.
- Professor Rubeish, are you in there?
- 真的很奇怪  - Rubeish 教授, 你在里面吗？
I can't stay here chatting, old boy.
Got to get after Rubeish.
我不能呆在这里闲聊了, 老家伙。得去找 Rubeish 了
Doctor, I forbid you to go off in that contraption.
博士, 我禁止你用那个奇怪的玩意跑掉
There's no telling where you'll finish up.
根本就说不准你会跑到什么地方去
Remember what happened to you on Metebelis III.
还记得你在 Metebelis 3号上面发生的事情吗？
- Well, I got there, didn't I?
- Yes, eventually, after several detours.
- 不管怎样, 我到了那儿, 对吧  - 是，最终是到了, 折腾了好几趟
Brigadier, a straight line may be the shortest distance
between two points,
准将, 直线或许是两点之间距离最短的
but it is by no means the most interesting.
但绝不是最有意思的
Goodbye, old chap.
再见, 老家伙
But, Doc...
但是, 博...
(WHOOSHING)
Well done, old girl. Absolutely on target.
做得好, 老丫头。完全跟住目标了
For once.
总算有一次
It's still only a police box.
但这只是一个警察亭啊
I must find a telephone.
我得找到一个电话
Sir Edward only has a puny force. He stands within his walls.
爱德华爵士的人力少得可怜, 只能龟缩在他的城墙里
If we can only breach them, Bloodaxe.
如果我们能渗透进去, Bloodaxe
We could cut Sir Edward's soldiers down
in less time than our rogues spend with their breakfasts.
我们就能砍倒他那些士兵, 快得比我们的伙计吃早饭的时间还少
It's those accursed walls, walls like these.
那些令人憎恨的城墙, 像这样的墙
But with Linx's new weapons...
只要有了 Linx 的新武器
Excuse me, could you tell me where the nearest telephone...
打扰一下, 你能告诉我最近的电话机在哪里...
He flees through the forest. Take him!
他逃到森林里去了, 抓住他！
After him, you dogs! Through the forest!
去抓他, 你们这些！往林子里去了！
Oh, it must be some sort of pageant. I say...
哦, 肯定是某种露天表演, 我说...
Hey, you there. Hey, what are you doing? Get off!
嘿, 停下, 嘿, 你要干什么？放开我
- Let go of me! Hey!
- How the blazes did she get here?
- 放开我, 嘿！  - 她怎么跑到这里来了
SARAH: Stop it!
停下！
Look, if this is a rag day joke, it's not funny!
嘿, 如果这是什么节日玩笑, 太过了啊！
- Come on!
- Let me go! I won't tell you...
- 来吧！  - 放开我！我不会告诉你...
(TWIG SNAPS)